### Contact

+91 9766006869 (Mobile) nitin.vegad14@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/nitin-vegadctrp™-73a37113 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Payroll
Human Resources
Talent Acquisition

### Languages

**English** 

Hindi

Marathi

Gujarati

### Certifications

Managing Employee Compensation Human Resources: Compensation and Benefits

Inclusive Leadership

Become an Inclusive Leader

Job Design, Compensation and Benefits

# Nitin Vegad, CTRP™

HR Shared Services - Compensation & Benefits, Global Payroll, HR Operations

Pune, Maharashtra, India

# Summary

A Certified Total Rewards Professional<sup>™</sup> with experience of 15+ years in HR Shared Services with exposure in Compensation, Benefits, Global Payroll and HR Operations. Played key role in setting up HR Shared Services and avid about delivering customer centric HR services to employees.

Having worked with diverse country Payroll, Compensation & Benefits and HR operations, I bring in with strong functional as well as operational knowledge in HR Shared Services. Worked on migration of payroll and other HR Shared Services Operations from US, APAC and EMEA regions to centralized work location. Well equipped with various payroll and HR systems like Oracle, Peoplesoft, SAP Success Factor, ADP Streamline Management, ADP Pro-B, Siebel, Neocase.

Got good exposure in working on IFC, SOX and external audits, controls and measures for HR Shared Services and also have worked and implemented various projects like Oracle Timesheet and Attendance, implementation of Leave Management on SAP Success Factor, HR Compliances, Digitization of HR records, Integration between HR and vendor system on process like Payroll, Leave Management and Benefits.

# Experience

**DNV GL** 

Head of Section - Compensation & Benefits, Payroll August 2020 - Present (2 years 2 months)

Pune, Maharashtra, India

Heading Compensation, Benefits & Payroll team for 25+ countries across IMEA, South Asia, North Asia and North America

- Part of core Global Centre Team (GSS HR) in Pune and lead transitioning of Global Payroll, Compensation and Benefits from Regional Offices to Pune.
- Supervise team who is responsible for processing payroll and managing compensation and benefits (Regions: India, Middle East, Africa, North & South Asia Pacific, Americas).
- Manage outsourced Payroll vendors and tax vendors to support the payroll processes with the focus being on timely and accurate delivery.
- Supervise the procedures of preparation, documentation and disbursement of all payroll checks, taxes, and employee benefit payments Oversee the statutory compliance.
- Be a strategic partner with Regional HR's and other support functions to ensure controls & policies are in place and provide solutions.
- Collaborate with Country Heads and Regional HR's on salary benchmarking, annual merit increase and variable pay cycle.
- Developing market insights in relevant businesses and interpreting benchmark data in relation to DNV business needs.
- Establishing professional partnerships with internal stakeholders and external vendors.
- HR transformation strategies and roadmap for digitalization of compensation and benefits at organization level.

# Tata Communications Manager Human Resource, Corporate HR June 2014 - August 2020 (6 years 3 months) Pune

Expertise in Global payroll, Compensation & Benefits. Working with other HRSS functions like EDM, Onboarding/ Offboarding team to analyze and redesign the process.

Successfully transited APAC payroll (countries Singapore, Hong Kong, Japan, Indonesia, Philippines, Australia & Malaysia) from Tata Singapore & UK Regional offices to centralized location in Pune.

#### Global Payroll

- Part of implementation team in collaborating payroll for APAC, Americas and EMEA regions to one global platform and its implementation with ADP Streamline.
- Perform L2 review and approve the payroll.
- Collaborate with Regional Centers and discuss on the challenges, initiatives within Payroll domain.

• Coordinates and lead the design of process improvements, systems development, implementation of best practice within Payroll

### Compensation & Benefits

- Support with Business Areas internal and external salary benchmarking.
- Participate in various salary survey with external players like Wills Tower Watson, Mercer, AON Hewitt.
- Setting up framework for internal applications related to compensation letter release, payroll Input Module application.
- Involved in salary normalization/Rationalization of employees covered in Appraisal Cycles – Annually and Quarterly, Preparing Comparison -ratio sheet for appraisal cycles.
- Derive on salary budgeting and salary frame modelling based on current geography situation (GDP, Inflation, Unemployment, internal pay grades etc.)
- Managing Time & Absence for APAC and India region and Vendor Governance.
- Design benefits globally by market benchmarking, evaluation of existing benefits, feasibility for new benefits

### **Allscripts**

Sr.Payroll Analyst June 2011 - June 2014 (3 years 1 month)

Payroll transition from US to India

Managing semi-monthly US payroll and UK, Singapore monthly payroll

Lead from payroll team to integrated HR and timekeeping module of Oracle.

Ensure documentation of all payroll activities and necessary forms, reports, etc. are filed in an organized and timely manner for the SOX audit purpose. Prepare and maintain SOP's are per the requirement of internal auditors & ensure all the process are followed as per the SOP guidlines

Mphasis an HP Company Sr.HRO Administrator (US & Australian Payroll) December 2007 - June 2011 (3 years 7 months)

Working on US Payroll on applications Peoplesoft. & Australian Payroll on SAP

### Education

## Dr. D.Y.Patil Vidyapeeth, Pune

Master of Business Administration - MBA, Human Resource · (2016 - 2018)

# Pune University

B.Com, Accounts & Taxation · (2004 - 2007)